hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
[Music]
at what age do we learn to have better
conversations with ourselves
[Music]
knowledge is power
reality is
[Music]
Let's uh if you don't mind let's start
with kind of just just a brief bio
background like like who are you what is
it that you do yeah sounds great sounds
great that question you know honestly is
always kind of uh
stumped me in some ways right because
it's such a big question but I'll
definitely dive into it
um
So currently
I am a small business owner so I operate
this company called Black Sheep business
Consulting uh I'm five and a half years
sober I'm feeling pretty decent overall
life life still has a lot of challenges
but
um that's kind of where I'm at right now
my story
um goes all over the place of course
um
you know I grew up in
um in a city where their middle class
had a great community of friends around
me and uh
from a young age like lots of people
maybe not like that many people but we
we drink a lot you know we yeah I think
I think a lot of
you know young guys kind of fell into
that space and and girls but um yeah so
as time progressed
um I got really interested in having big
goals in life you know I wanted to be an
athlete that was really my overarching
goal
um and honestly like I really believe I
want to bring positive change to the
world so it's like I'm Gonna Be An
Athlete but I'm gonna do something with
it
um
and that was way more General than than
it is now now I have much more clear
objectives of how it could help but yeah
so as I went through life you know I
just kept digging into
um this cycle of addiction really in
many different ways
um
drinking lots
it's pretty aggressive too honestly
growing up and um
as time went on uh the the pro athlete
thing didn't work out
wasn't big enough
to be a forward in rugby was it fast
enough to be a back so there's two
positions there forwards and backs and
uh yeah I kept getting injured so I
around 18 or 19 I I stepped out of
um out of that position of you know
wanting to go pro and
um I started working with my dad's
business full-time whereas
you know from 10 to 18 I was just
part-time
so he had a property service business I
started to get more and more into that I
always loved business in the back of my
mind I was always like
business business that was the other the
other option for me right so dove into
that for a few years
um operated business for three years
just the uh
the the alcoholism was growing I was
like I think it was the
um
it was like the definition of work hard
play hard you know I would and
especially when you're 19 years old and
20 you're like oh I can drink I can
drink water and then I can go to work
and I'm fine when you get a little older
and you're like whoa what's happening
here so yeah you know I I did that it
was awesome I I learned so much through
those a few years there from like 18 to
21 and then by the time I got to 21 I
realized the business was not
sustainable the way I had set it up I
really wanted to scale the business and
it wasn't really happening Plus at the
same time I was pretty fatigued and
stressed because
I hadn't had learned about wearing
yourself out which does which does
happen so you need to always be
conscious of that I believe
so I I stepped out of it and my dad
agreed and um because he was kind of
helping like mentoring me sort of as I
was going through that stage of my life
and he agreed he's like yeah step out of
it so stepped out of it
you know 21-22 I had a bit of cash there
because I had gone out of the business
and traveled a lot so I from like 21 to
26 I travel tons like there's always
more traveling to do I'm not the most
well-traveled person but I'm not the
least well traveled person were you
traveling for work or or Leisure or a
bit above Leisure Leisure yeah yeah
um definitely sure yeah
um and uh
yeah I remember one time I uh the first
trip I went on my own I arrived in
Stockholm Sweden
on like a Friday night at like 10 p.m or
something
and I was there to party anyways and the
guard like I walked up and like in the
purpose of the trip there's like this
Swedish card this woman there and I said
I'm here to party out and
she's like that's not a valid reason to
enter Sweden unfortunately and I'm like
for leisure
anyway I know that was like the
beginning of my 21 year old trip to
Europe that reminds me of have you seen
Superbad with uh yeah but I I should
have I know yeah he has he has this
scene where uh like a cop asked him he
has a fake ID and it just says McLovin
as his name it's ridiculous it's a
hilariously stupid movie you should
totally watch it but um uh like they
asked how old he is and he says old
enough to party that's his response is
just so stupid but yeah that's awesome
yeah that's straight out of that movie
my response yeah but
um yeah so you know it traveled a lot
there
um
just kept digging into
a substance abusion abuse and whatnot
came back my plan was so in one sense
what happened there was awesome because
I really
stepped into the idea that I'm not that
concerned about from a young age I'm not
that concerned about
you know letting go of a business at a
crucial time in your life right because
when you usually when you leave High
School you're like what am I going to do
with my life that's one of the biggest
questions at plagues you and as time
goes on you're either like
in your mind going
I've got this or I don't have this or I
have some parts of it or I don't you're
less about like what am I doing more
about like okay where am I where am I at
internally where am I at maybe even
financially where am I at you know it's
relationship so
a lot of people are plagued by that
question and rightfully so and I was
more like you know what I'm gonna be
fine whatever I do I'm I I have a few
different ideas of what I'm going to go
into
this isn't right in business right now
and let's do something else so anyways
long story short traveled Lots love to
chat about that maybe a little bit later
uh on the show but um
yeah I mean uh as time went on
um I
um started working in utilities and just
got into
more and more
um
uh recreational activities with
different substances whatnot and then
really got into that for a few years
from like 24 to 27 and then I had this
life-changing event
um when I was 27 I believe
and that's what kind of set me on the
current trajectory I'm on
okay yeah yeah I definitely want I feel
like this is a a phenomenal you know we
could spend some time on this
life-changing event if you don't mind
because uh I feel like many
I mean for me I had a similar you know
around that age where like it's like
everything seemed to change and um I
don't know if you're familiar but uh
like in the artist world in the world of
musicians I might have mentioned this to
you on our call there's like this 27
Club
um yeah so there's like like Nirvana
Kurt Cobain uh you know it's essentially
like I'm gonna party like a rock star
like you know live every day you're
gonna die whatever like so you basically
are under the understanding that you're
kind of gonna die when you're 27.
Hendrix too there's all these different
ones yeah there's so many this is
something weird with our psychology
there too for sure
definitely definitely yeah okay so yeah
no that was definitely so yeah what what
changed what happened and yeah let's
talk about life before and after
definitely definitely
so I really enjoyed going to White Caps
games so it's this uh the soccer team
and uh I was actually there with my dad
it was a season ticket holder and um
but you wouldn't sit in the seats you'd
stand
because it was the Super section so I
was at a game and by the way I'm
completely wrong in all this I shouldn't
have done this but it's just this is
kind of what happened
um so is that the scheme second half
usually no one would be in the seats to
the left of me because the whole section
was just like supporters and anyways No
One issues in that in those two seats
for whatever reason
um
Yeah so basically there were the
gentlemen next to me that were standing
there and I guess they had like they
were standing but there was a half drank
water bottle in the cup holder to the
left of me so being
you know inebriated I just thought Ah
that's not a big deal because I had
these two beers and I dropped it behind
their seat
um which of course I should not have
done and then I put one of the beers I
was holding in there as the game
continued
uh one of them brought it up to me and
you know was rather upset and I
I believe Apollo I would apologize and I
you know said that I was in the wrong
but who knows
um
as time went on and I was pretty loud
because a lot of people in that section
are really loud and chanting doing
things
they continue to bring up the issue and
call whole names and whatnot and it
really continued and
anyways
um you know some back and forth happened
and eventually a fight broke out
um again
eight Sonic broken record but I'm
completely wrong in this and yeah but uh
in the end you know the police came down
um
I was in like a pretty violent
fight
um between a bunch of different
individuals there
um and in the end I was charged with you
know three uh charged but not convicted
in the end uh so charged with three
counts of assault and um
uh was asked to not return to the uh The
Event Center there the stadium
and as time went on
I had a court date in October
um that was in August and
um
in September I just like by fluke called
a number for lawyer to send you as a
lawyer and it happened to be somebody I
went to high school with who I know was
incredible
at law and very intelligent because one
of my best friends is a lawyer and he
would always tell me that he was like
leading the university and just just
incredible so it was interesting how
that worked out that was on a Monday
he checked my file this is at like 7 45
PM so most people aren't working you
know answering calls at that time
um And he as of the Friday the
prosecutor had reviewed the files
prior to going into court and he put put
out like a
um
put out a
like a court order that I would have to
follow
um pretty much stating that I would not
drink
um throughout the entire court
proceedings like for the next however
many months or years
I didn't see it because I'm not checking
that system and there was like a warrant
out for my arrest so it was pretty
incredible this gentleman was able to
communicate this to me search it find it
like communicate it to me make a plan
with me
um secure me as a client
right security is a client uh and then
go on to over the next few days speak to
the prosecutor set up a time for us to
go into court
and meet me outside of the courtroom
walk me through without getting arrested
because technically I should have been
arrested at that point in time so no
handcuffs put on me whatsoever he walked
me through because he knew all the
different security guards and whatnot at
the courthouse and uh
and then leading up to that talk to me
about the court order and say to me you
know
if you want to do this and if you're
going to agree to it if you
plan to drink through this process don't
agree to it because
um you will face potentially jail time
if you're if you're caught drinking
throughout the court proceedings here
over the next few months
so inside I felt friggin saved because I
was like this is the first time
finally something's forcing me to do
this I've felt inside multiple times
that I have this issue and it's like
it's such a personal thing right you
could drink I truly believe you could
drink every single day and you could not
be an alcoholic it's or you could drink
once a year and you could be an
alcoholic or once every 20 years like so
it's such a personal thing and inside I
had tried to stop my family didn't
enough to play my family but they never
thought they just thought it was a joke
like oh Kevin's fine but but inside I
really I really wanted something to like
get in my way so I was like holy geez I
literally felt saved because I had to
stop drinking there's probably a little
bit of fear there too at the beginning
but I also remember feeling that I can
actually remember where I was standing I
was on the top of a landfill because
that's where I was working I was doing
different uh utilities and piping
because landfills have a lot of methane
gas so
and it was kind of cool because just the
way the sun was out it was like this
really interesting setting I always
remember just like walking and being on
the phone
and just like yeah and thinking about it
so anyways from that point on yeah it
was from that point on it was
um it was Serenity right it was it was
turning myself over and
um
saying I have an issue and I'm willing
I'm willing for something outside of
myself to guide me and as Court went on
as everything went on I went through the
steps of
you know volunteering
um
I realized I had a huge anxiety issue
like huge and that's that's really what
was driving me to drink was the fact
that
inside I was nervous I was scared and I
was I didn't feel right like a lot of us
right a lot everyone
feels like that right so it came to the
service so it took about eight months to
go through the whole process
um part of it because they kept throwing
it out for a little bit so they'd be
like ah it's almost Christmas let's wait
till after Christmas and see if this guy
messes up or let's let's you know let's
let's kick down the road a little bit
let's
and um
yeah for me that's just all external to
me and
it was amazing and positive in a lot of
different ways so as we got to the end
one of the
um victims or complainants
um you know just was not very happy
briefly so and um
they pushed it and they were like hey we
want to see more done so
the last month was like okay I went to
court and they were like okay
it's gonna be an intense month basically
this is what my lawyer kind of told me
there's going to be you know you'll be
volunteering at where the court says not
where you want to volunteer like they're
going to tell you where
um so the X amount of hours there
um there's going to be drug and alcohol
counseling uh and a few other items and
you're going to have a parole officer
that you have to report to for that
month if you do all this then we should
be good to move forward out of this and
drop the charges as long as you're
remorseful and move forward
um
so in that month that all happened kind
of on a Monday sort of leading up to
that you know maybe a week or so and
then something like that and then on the
Monday went into court boom
um and coming over to court you know I
met with a parole officer spoke with
them I called the place that I was
supposed to go to and they were like hey
look this is for people who have like
serious
um you know
subscription addictions you know downers
uh there's a wait list so they're like
look we we can't just let you in right
now so I communicated that to the parole
officer then they said hey what about uh
Alcoholics Anonymous there's a meeting
you know tonight and I was like great
you know I inside I was like yes
Something's Gonna
save me something like that so
I went into this meeting and I had four
of those once once a week
um
for that month and uh it was so cool the
first meeting like most people in AAA
you're just like what is this it was an
all men's meeting which was great
because I've heard
that in like men's and women's meetings
a lot of people get distracted they're
like oh how am I how am I appearing and
how am I whereas in men's or if you're
you know just in a woman's one like it
you're just focused on just being honest
and just sharing your truth right so
it was great and but the first meeting
is really weird because everyone is
for the most part sober everyone's very
nice and everyone's laughing and for
someone who's like
a male who grew up drinking and like
you know a lot of sports teams which but
you're just being like a degenerate
maybe and like drinking doing this and
that like to go to a meeting where
everyone's sober in a room and just like
laughing and enjoying themselves is very
strange it's like you're on another
planet really yeah yeah
yeah really and everyone says the same
thing too everyone always goes like
first meeting I was like you guys are
something's up here yeah did I walk into
a cult room on accident like what is
this seriously and like aha yeah I yeah
I didn't know what was happening so and
I also didn't know if they had someone
from the courts there that was gonna
like listen so I was like I did not know
what so I was like can I are you guys
all real like are you guys because I had
my core papers too and they're like hey
nobody knows anyone from your court
pretty much something to that degree
share
chair and just whatever so like you're
safe you can you can communicate freely
you know you don't have to have guards
up you know exactly so you know I shared
a bit and as the weeks went on
um you know after the first or second
meeting there's this guy called John
and uh you know he just kind of said hey
it's all good it's all good and just
started to like call me and that was one
of pieces that I used to battle the
anxiety thing and my therapist that I
reached out to and I still work with
today
said a similar thing right that's where
I was really shook I don't know what
happened to his job but I and that
calming for psychopathic
it's all good that's what I really
needed so anyways as time went on I've
pretty much stayed with that group since
um the charges were were dropped
um which is
you know a blessing in many ways at the
same time I I'm very very remorseful for
what happened and
grateful that I'm able to see everything
from this new new light you know and um
yeah times time has gone and uh just
you know I'm still going to that same
meeting that same Monday night 8 PM
men's meeting and uh still seeing that
therapist that I met just right around
that same time and started seeing an
anxiety therapist
she's fantastic and life's continued on
and I've
that's where really you know this
spiritual part which I think is you know
great for your show and for your
audience to kind of chat about it like
that's where that
really came to light like where the
light started shining real bright and
where I came to my own beliefs upon
personal beliefs in that regard so
yeah
um
yeah okay wow so so I mean when I'm when
I'm sensing from you what I'm hearing
from you is just like this overflowing
cup of just gratitude for this situation
you know it's like like you you're
trying to find this way of of speaking
about this thing that actually happened
you know you made an ass out of yourself
when you were drunk at a baseball game
you know or at a sporting event and um
you know and and you don't want to talk
about it in a sense of like I was in the
right you know I definitely hear you
saying like man I was just totally
unconscious to my actions you know and
and um this this anxiety Factor really
really sneaks in here on me because I
wonder about this like I feel
so many of us you know myself included
in my own Journey
um like you you're almost like you don't
you don't necessarily realize why you're
drinking so much like why can't I have
an okay time without the drinking like
what it like and then when you hear
someone say well I had an anxiety
problem I was like running away from
someone I'm trying not to feel this like
uncomfortable anxiety that's like still
in here all the time trying to shut it
up or whatever it's hard to hard to hear
that unless you're on the other side and
then you can kind of admit oh yeah I had
that you know that I had that anxiety
too it was eating me alive
totally and like I always with all of
this it's like
most people we speak about this and hey
I want to quote a but this is my own
kind of thing so
most people are in the middle of
everything they're in an okay job and
I'm not trying to down play like people
in general but just they're stuck in the
middle it's like it's everything's okay
maybe with the relationship's okay maybe
they feel okay about themselves maybe
their goals are okay they're kind of
going for everything's okay it's just
kind of in the middle
one great thing about going all out
in life is that you're gonna fail and
you're gonna fail real big sometimes
like it's like things are going to blow
up potentially yeah figuratively
speaking and
that was kind of the crash course that I
was on and this was like the huge big
major
fail
and
through that I was able to realize
you know that I had a huge that I was
way too aggressive that I had an anxiety
challenge like a really big one that I
was
using alcohol from a very young age to
like numb myself right majorly not
myself and other substances and
so that's just the one like if I could
share one thing with anyone who's kind
of in the middle on stuff it's like go
all out just because the failure like at
that time I was like this is the end of
everything this this how am I going to
get through it that was always a plan
right like how am I gonna get through
this in life how am I going to get
through that and
by letting everything blow up you're
able to kind of just step back and go
okay where was I completely wrong but if
you just are always in the middle
you're just always going to stay there
right and that's a great thing about
alcoholics and maybe anyone who's it
could maybe even extending outside of
Alcoholics like somebody who's in
a relationship or maybe somebody who's
abusive himself it's like when you're
able to kind of step out of it you're
able to
examine it with like a new light so yeah
it's not always the worst to kind of
run into these major issues because you
can you can learn so much more but just
from the alcohol standpoints like are we
grateful alcoholics
or even like uh in any in even in like
relationships we're in a better
relationship are you grateful that you
were in that bad relationship
the idea is that we are grateful because
without this trauma and without these
challenges we wouldn't have been able to
learn this right so can you imagine just
being in the middle of everything oh
I've got I'm going from one okay
relationship to another okay one my
job's okay it could be better it could
be worse you're never going to learn
anything right so anyways it's just
going all out and almost like
my the way I think is really visual
and
in rugby so you play a lot of rugby we
would always talk about
when you're going to crash a ball so
you're taking the ball it's kind of like
football in a sense you you're looking
to go as far forward as you can before
you go to the floor before you go to the
ground
taking somebody else with you like
literally grabbing one of your fellow
teammates and running in so that they
help push you like another you know a
yard forward
that is what I always think about when I
think about
um like failing in life is like
with your team go as far as you can
crash and then get up again and do it
again right like so anyways it's kind of
a physical way of thinking about it but
that just always comes to mind in in
business and a lot of different things
this is reference right you know just
taking something to the extremes that
you can learn from it right even for
marketing like you do a lot of marketing
with the business
there's a guy called Alex harmasian he
says marketing is just a fancy word a
fancy nine letter word for test it's all
you're doing right you're just testing
how something works so anyways it's it's
it's good it's good to fail it's good to
fails yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah and I
like that I feel like what was coming to
mind is this um and I've said it on here
a lot and I butchered it just as many
times um I forget exactly if it was like
Vikings or what but back in the day
there's this story of um you know
Landing
getting a bunch of ships together the
Army lands boom and they all start you
know approaching they're approaching the
enemy of camp and then they they look
back in the leader of it has burnt all
the boats he's burnt the ships and he's
and they're like what are you doing and
he's like we can't lose now like we
can't go back there's no option to go
back you know and so sometimes you
almost got to like hear that you got to
hear that catalyst is a great word I
feel like Catalyst for like um you know
this A Spiritual Awakening or really
just the Catalyst for living through a
more true version of who you are in a
lot of ways you know and and you know I
guess what I think um how did you I mean
it seems to you like you had this this
beautiful moment of being like at the
Waste Control place you know and and uh
and you said like these you notice this
is the colors in the sky and whatever
you know it's yeah how did you
because a lot of this thing like like
for me with my own addictions with my
own you know I've had plenty of plenty
of way too late nights you know multiple
nights a weekend and uh you know I get
off I'm at a club and I'm DJing and then
it's not what that's when the party
starts and it's 10 a.m and I'm still
awake and I'm talking everybody's ear
off because I've been doing a bunch of
coke and and just drinking 25 beers and
all that stuff and um a lot of times
it's like I have this intuition inside I
have this like voice going what are you
doing dude you don't need this like you
know you don't want to do this this
doesn't make you feel good you've
learned this lesson already how many how
many more times must you learn it you
know
how do you how do you think that you
finally were able to hear that voice
because I think so many
once we're on the other side we can go
yeah man I had that voice too I had that
intuition trying to tell me like you're
not doing the thing yes totally so a few
different things a
you can never
if even things first you have to ask
yourself a series of questions right
are you in a place where you're addicted
to what you're doing right it's like
it's a yes or no okay so you have to ask
yourself like hey do I have a problem
where I actually need to turn myself
over
to something else because doing it alone
I don't I honestly don't believe Works
personally
it I can't answer it for the person who
just thinks that they have like a really
strong habit for it I can only say for
if you actually and this extends to like
relationships extends like say you're
working at a place and your your boss is
horrible and you've tried to like
complain make it better but it's not
working you're in a situation regardless
where something's insane
and you need to get out of it you need
to ask yourself whether that's alcohol
drugs relationship anything spiritually
maybe you're in a religion or you're
practicing something that isn't working
right ask yourself whether it's Insanity
whether you need to get out of it or not
if you're willing to do whatever it
takes to get out of it to make your life
better
then you need to take the next step for
myself and for anyone this might extend
to other things so for myself it was
the first part so what's the whole
junkyard thing like sorry not junker
button the whole
um landfill scene that was just like the
question I asked myself then was this is
leading up to them you know I worked a
job I
pavement taxes for the most part I did
everything I just used a lot of
substances on my own time and traveled
and was like
kind of crazy in that regard I like to
go to really dangerous places anyways
slightly dangerous and we can do that in
a bit but
um
I asked myself on that landfill the
question was this
okay tough guy I literally like said
that to myself sorry it's kind of
embarrassing but you know
you think you're this and that because I
would I would go to these sporting
events for the soccer thing and I would
see the other teams and I would like
lift them off and this and that like I
was
anyways one time for example they like
they were walking down the street after
a game and they had like a sticker and
they jumped up and put it on a on a um a
Lamppost like really high and I've
so I should be laughing at this this is
a different game by the way I ran up and
like jumped really high and grabbed it
and I just put it in my box and I'm like
not in our city like this and that and
and anyways but the whole thing is
I was in many ways out of control I
consider myself be a hooligan I said to
myself
where are you going to take this at that
point in time like that was kind of one
of the questions because it wasn't like
an immediate call of hey look this is
here like we were kind of going back and
forth for a bit so that was running
through my head I was like are you
willing to keep going down that path are
you going to realize right now have this
issue
you need to like listen to this
excellent legal advice and you know you
have a drug and alcohol problem as well
and this is like a Saving Grace and I
was able to go
okay I'm willing to try this because
inside I've always believed in good in
myself right I'm like I need I need to
do what is good I need to do what is
right so I it was a
a step into Serenity where I was like
okay I'm gonna try whatever it takes
here because I know this is the right
path
so that's kind of where it started
[Music]
yeah I hear that I hear that yeah you
have to you have to kind of like
yeah you have to almost get out you have
to get out of your own way in a lot of
aspects to like let that other thing
come through
oh yeah and that's like in the program
about and I I say this but it this
extends to like pretty much
anything right like anything else where
it's like you have a problem where you
need to get out of something
the first step in AAA which again I
think is translatable is admitting that
it's an issue boom you know I this is
out of my control I'm powerless over
this this thing this whatever this
addiction is whatever it is it's I I
can't do it and it's not working and I
need
I need something else to say basically
and then I don't want to approach
through the steps but I know from there
it goes like I do it a lot and everyone
knows all the different codes and the
there's not codes but like all the
different steps and for me I'm just a
sponge I listen and then I try to
implement in my life and that's my truth
is like
I believe
that
you can do things wrong all the time but
if inside you're literally trying your
best it's all good right which is the
opposite of what we're told in public
school and everything it's like
don't take risks you need to if you
don't get this number on here you're a
bozo and you're this and you're going to
go down this path and it's like the
older I get the more I realize that's
the biggest freaking lie ever and it's
like if that was bad when I was growing
up
like what's hap what's happening now so
anyway so yeah but you know it's
yeah just I I was able to start going
down that path and um of just like
opening myself to other things
and that's what's cool about it is
over the last five and a half years the
number one thing that's like
kind of risen I want to say over top of
everything because my sobriety and
um you know
my religious beliefs and whatnot that's
like number one but the biggest theme
is Taoism
and the idea of just like energy good
bad evil and just that the universe is
always moving and changing
um
and resistance is one of the biggest
things that you want to step away from
and this is what I see in a all the time
and I think we can all see this in our
lives and with like their friends and
our family
we have people in the program that can't
get it they can't get it when I talk to
them about their
their spiritual connection whether it's
like hey I believe in
spirituality I believe in whenever I go
into the woods something speaks to me
and I feel connected with myself like I
need to go Earth or I just need to
meditate or I like to read books about
math or I'm Buddhist or I'm Islamic I
Believe In Christ like whatever it is
um
you need to find something God is God I
believe is real and it's not you that's
the most important thing right when we
when we step away from like that's
something that is said a lot in the
program is like all you need to know is
that God is real and it's not you that's
not to to put yourself down because I
believe that God is in everything to an
extent but it's just to say Hey you know
when something great happens
you don't have to say hey I did that I
did that
hey something external to me did it and
if what you're doing the work you're
putting in each and every day is
building on that positivity then you're
on the right track right as soon as you
start saying like anything that happens
is my fault like every single time like
if I fall asleep for a meeting that's
100 my fault if this happened like as
soon as you keep you're putting yourself
on a pedestal where you're like you're
God the reality is that it has to be
something external to yourself so
anyways that's just like yeah yeah you
thought you had all this control but in
the end it's like almost the key is to
let go of the control and trust that
whatever just happened is exactly what's
supposed to happen there's something you
needed to learn there's something oh
you're stuck behind this red light well
maybe it stopped you from getting
T-boned at the next light you know what
I mean there's little things that I I
was thinking of I have this line of
poetry I've written find a place to pray
to something bigger than you and your
stories
and and it's like
so so often we we're so mean to
ourselves and like you were saying with
the letter grade you know we're kind of
in in the the Western World of thinking
it's like you either do good or you're
bad or you're you get that big old F or
you're failing and it's like you stop
trying to take your letter report card
at all times stop trying to judge
yourself on if you're doing well enough
like like you said inside if if you know
you're trying your best like you're
really just like doing the thing and
you're being honest about that with
yourself then I think you're being led
to the water you know that's that's
exactly it that's exactly it and that's
where like the biggest thank you ever
goes out to like you know any teacher
anyone's ever had that goes okay I know
they taught us this in like teaching
school you know in the University but
I'm gonna go a little bit outside of
this curriculum and make somebody you
know believe in themselves who might be
having a bad day and like just because
that's the real that's the good stuff
right like like we can we can sit around
be robots and just be like oh
you're failing or you're smart you're
agree with this but
um yeah exploring that other side of
things is just so key right and uh
there's so much of that there's so much
of that happening and it's great right
like everything everything we knew as a
culture 50 years ago how much of it is
completely different now right like I
just I love I want to derail too much
but I just love how
you know we're beginning to explore
psychedelics like I never I've never
done psychedelics that I know of
um one time I had something one time I
had some weed lace or something and now
I mean yeah I mean wheat in itself can
be so certainly a psychological
experience especially um Edibles Edibles
are actually like five times more
psychoactive than uh just smoking the
THC so it's definitely you're in for an
adventure but if if you're not in the
right set in setting you're just trying
to constantly stay grit stay
stay exactly who you are when the trick
to psychedelics is to let go of who you
are and experience you know the god that
is the Dao you know experience the
everything that is actually happening
and then you go oh I'm not just my body
I'm not my thoughts I'm not you know I'm
much more than this that's what
psychedelics are kind of you know
intended to open up in this
it's great like I
I am such a fan of all that and I'm just
like why when I was doing all that did I
not try any of that stuff just yeah
anyways but that's that is
so awesome and uh yeah
well um yeah yeah dude I just think it's
incredible thank you for sharing that
thank you for bringing vulnerability you
know to I'm sure it's you know maybe it
gets easier you know day after day year
after year to like share that story but
um you know if you're anything like me
it's it's been a heck of us putting my
foot in my mouth and stumbling over it
and saying the wrong things and finally
like you know if uh you know I'm 31 now
in my sort of my sort of catalyst to to
you know
be myself and have some sort of
connection with something bigger than me
started around the same time and it's
just been a heck of a time trying to
figure out what I think about it and
what I mean about it and how I can find
grounding now and um I think that's the
gift of it is stumbling out loud and
that's I think a podcast is a beautiful
thing to um it's not a five minute
interview you know it's not a it's not a
you know you have to say the exact same
right words and you have to express
yourself super clearly it's like think
out loud what you're kind of going
through and we can resonate with that
you know that's it's a beautiful thing
it's so great I completely agree I've
probably been on it over the last like
since covet maybe five podcasts
something like that and it's that every
single time what is it about podcasts
that
you know just makes us I think is what
you said right it's that it's not it's
not super short you're able to dive into
it and like
you know
if we can strip the podcast thing away
okay
should we just as humans be doing more
of of catching up with people right like
it doesn't doesn't it bring you back to
like how you should be feeling just like
discussing everything and getting into
everything have you um sorry to cut you
off go ahead no no that's awesome uh
yeah I am I mean I I think of you know
who and what we are like whatever
through whatever you process we've
gotten here I'm sure there was a time
where it's you know we're talking around
campfires you know after we've hunted
all day and and uh now we're just
talking on campfires and I feel like you
know uh cave paintings and all this sort
of stuff is is storytelling is is how
our psychological you know um layout is
is what our experience is is a story
it's storytelling and it's not about
getting it right it's not about reading
a story over here and taking your note
cards and then you come over here and
you say exactly because you remembered
it perfectly that's not that's not real
that's a mimic version of it you know um
do you find that
the way that you just even the things
that you talk about you know as much as
I would totally agree that you know when
I would drink a lot um I've only been
sober for a few months now but I feel
like the last few years it's been like
just a you know a beer or two
um I've really kind of like really just
been over it for a while but I'm still
trying to like figure out exactly what
it is and and what's interesting this is
a side side rail um yeah the reason why
I kind of like perked up when you first
reached out to me is actually my my last
beer there's this place in Austin called
The Black Sheep Lodge and my last beer
was there and I was sitting there and I
I'm I'm a natural introvert I love to
like work on poetry and write music and
stuff like at the but I like being in
these loud environments sometimes we'll
have headphones in and uh so one of my
favorite things to do go to a dive bar
write some poetry have two beers and
have a meal and uh I I was like it was
in December actually and I was there and
I was drinking the beer and I just knew
this is my last beer I was like huh well
this is interesting it wasn't like a mad
at myself self it wasn't like oh yeah I
knew this was coming here it is you know
um
uh oh and so so my roundabout Point um
would be do you find yourself like the
person you were before like even though
you have this social lubricant right we
love that word of you know you have some
beers and suddenly you're like open and
you're just BS and you're connecting
with all these people and whatever there
is that and that is a beautiful thing
but I find that the quality of my
conversations the things that I'm
talking about things really light me up
inside like what is this all about you
know like what is this like how have you
experienced life so far and what have
you learned you know in the last couple
months I find way more access to
enthralling conversations
um when I'm not
have you know just drinking and
conversating um you know not not to not
to hate on that because they're just it
is great but so your conversations
before and after do you find that
they're vastly different
well on that on that point one thing
Okay so
I've got a few different groups of
friends
pretty much they're all they're all just
friends right but like different
different kind of circles but they could
all be at one party and they'd all get
along right but just you know a few
different circles so basically my main
circle of friends as I was drinking and
diving into
you know substance abuse they really
distance themselves for me because you
know when you're 21 it's normal maybe I
don't want to put like a number on it
but and then as time goes on people just
kind of you know grow out of it I was
like
kind of growing into it you know in my
mid to 20s
um
and they distance themselves from the
end
a few months into sobriety we were at my
buddy's stag and um
you know they said something that really
inspired me they're just like hey we uh
something along the lines of like
we love the sober Kevin like we we like
accept and we love and we're like huge
fans of the sober Kevin like they said
that and I've known like my friends go
back like when I was like two and five
and like you know all you know growing
growing up and some of the like the
gentleman who said that for example from
like 18 you know but one of my newer
friends technically on paper you know
but
hearing that really did something to me
because a huge part of all this a huge
part of getting sober at the beginning
was going to my family and this is going
to relate in one second going to my
family saying I have this problem I'm
not like I'm not kidding and them
acknowledging and saying we recognize
that you have this problem and we
recognize that and we support you that
was huge getting sober and going okay
now that I'm freaking sober and I feel
like naked I'm like here okay maybe I
can I'm more not alert but like you know
I'm not going to lose my keys so that's
cool but overall I'm like do I do I look
okay am I alright and just both saying
yeah you're fine the way you are and
then chilling out that individual like
my vibration I guess just like chilling
in a part of it I will say was taking
um medications uh like I teach super
super small even to this day super small
one
called peroxetine and it's like uh
um
you know anxiety one it's actually
technically an antidepressant but it
it's supposed to almost make you like
sleepy like really chill like and I have
the like the most mild one it works so
well
um
and you know part of that could be the
chemical side of it right who knows
maybe I was just born I don't I don't
know or maybe if it works it works man
that's great exactly exactly so
you know with regards to the the
conversating part of it like to be able
to get to the point that was my goal
when I literally went so about eight
months in right when the court thing was
pretty much you know ending that's when
I was like okay I need tickets it was
long enough or I'm like I have this
anxiety issue like I was really
concerned and I found this anxiety
clinic and started going there and um
yeah that's that's when I started diving
into all that but um yeah the main goal
that I said to my therapist was like
what's you know what's what's your
objective with all this and I just said
I want to be able to stand in a circle
of people
not think at all about
the anxiety side of it and I just want
to be able to just talk and just be a
positive version of myself at work and
even personally and I want like that's
that's my goal and today to be able to
be there where
I like am I going to say a hundred or a
hundred times something like that no but
like maybe the one time that I'm not
it's like a tenth of what it was before
or like you know one percent what so
it's just way better and uh
yeah I the huge part of it is what we've
gone back going back to what we spoke
about before is stepping out of yourself
you know being a little bit naked in the
sense of like all right I'm gonna try
this new thing and it's not gonna be me
if it goes well it's not gonna be me if
it goes bad it's not gonna be me I'm
just going to learn from it and I'm just
going to kind of pull myself and this is
literally what my therapist said
if I'm in a setting where lots of people
are coming at me they're asking lots of
questions at once and that's a situation
that we used to invoke a lot of anxiety
I'm going to like pull myself out of
that and slow it down pull myself out so
I'm going to look at it like from the
ceiling kind of from the side
I'm sure look at everyone and I don't
have to answer it away just because
their energies like that I don't have to
and then I'm gonna choose one person I'm
just gonna start talking to one person
last a question and I'm just gonna just
just discuss with them you know like I
just because somebody runs up to you
with
um a microphone and they're like hey and
they start asking you questions doesn't
mean you have to be at that same
wavelength it's like um I'm good so
anyway so with with the whole you know
social side of things
all that combined has helped in the
number one thing is just stepping out of
yourself and trying other things you
know okay so like if uh if therapy isn't
working maybe I need to talk to my
doctor maybe maybe there's a
subscription maybe maybe if the
subscriptions aren't working
you should talk to a naturopath right
keep trying new things it's something
outside of yourself and that's where
your faith which for me is what the
biggest thing in life my faith
um that's where that starts to grow
and that's where you can realize
how much you are a part of it everything
else how much everything is a part of
you and how
the thing that's inside you that's like
your soul how you can actually start to
like learn from that right and like be
inspired by that
um and appreciate it right that was that
was the biggest part of my journey where
things really start to get better was
when externally and this is why it's so
important for ourselves to help other
people right because we need it we need
on the bad day somebody to say hey
you're doing amazing if you're doing
amazing like if don't lie to people but
like but you know that that kindness and
whatnot it's so key because we need that
so
the more we are genuinely caring and
this
this is where the whole social media
thing of like hey let's film somebody
and we're going to give them money it's
like oh that's so fit like it's like I
know it's just for clicks and it's for
this it's for that and I love there's
this one guy on Tick Tock who makes fun
of it and just makes it just takes it to
a whole other level and I love that but
it's sad right but anyways but on but
what we can do in our real lives I think
is really explore that right try to step
out of ourselves you know go to that
meeting that you know you've been
thinking about that you're kind of
uncomfortable about uh go uh watch a
movie
um date someone if you're single date
someone you
wouldn't usually date right like just
try
try to step out of what you're currently
doing to see things in that light
um
yeah and that's that's what really led
me down that path and as I've done that
I've been able to really feel inside
myself
who I am and
the self-love part of it was the biggest
thing in my first eight months of
sobriety had come home sometimes
just start bawling crying because I
never taken care of the thing inside of
me it was always like there's like a
Guns and Roses song I was just like okay
I've got this time off my hands are
gonna sweat I'm gonna buy this buy that
start consuming I had never just gone
like hey it's cold outside
I'm gonna bring a jacket like I always
had that mentality of just like
beating myself down so I could be as
strong as possible in lots of different
ways but there's never just like hey I'm
gonna take care of this a little bit and
that's just
the environment I kind of grew up on it
and it's my own doing too right it's
myself but um yes as time went on I
started to really look at that and um
and it helps right and to this day I'm
still a lot of those Character defects
from six years ago from my childhood
they're still there but because I'm able
to step out of it and look at it and
improve some of the like I don't say
easy wins but some of the first initial
stuff that's there
I'm able to have those skills in like a
bit of a skill set for life right like
function to function it's really cool
it's really cool because when you when
you start to go down that path you start
to learn so much more too right and um
and it's that much more embarrassing
though when you're well it's not it's
not really that embarrassing because I
do I do feel that I have a level of
humility in life right humility is so
key to like a program right um being
able to laugh at yourself and just but
um yeah but before you were probably so
afraid of that embarrassment like you're
like well I'll do anything to not you
know feel that embarrassment that I know
is is available to me if I if I step out
of my comfort zone exactly exactly but
over time it gets great right it's kind
of fun to be like
you know that self-deprivating side of
it with my first so I had two therapists
the first one I went to was like
it did not go well it's like I think
your first meeting with a therapist
should be like an interview in many
regard like it really is right it's like
two I always think my head's like two
dogs like sniffing each other in a park
for the first time and that therapist
was just like
anyways very I don't want to Bachelor
therapist but like very fixed and like
hey that's self-deprivating like that's
that but I think we need to be able to
laugh at ourselves and be like Oh I'm
like uh I'm not very great at that at
all but you know but um anyways yeah I
didn't that that first one didn't go
very well and then uh the director of
the clinic was like
okay I'm gonna give you to somebody else
who's like their problem child because
this therapist like rented a room sort
of a thing at this amazing clinic and
um
and didn't get along that well with the
director but was just like amazing what
she did so she was like okay I'm gonna
take you from like my Apprentice who
like I'm making the most money off to
the person that's actually gonna work
for you
um anyway the person in the double white
Outback you know he's a therapist but
he's in the trailer you know like yeah I
actually just watched yesterday on the
plane I just watched Goodwill Hunting
have you watched that I love that movie
such a fantastic movie I definitely
cried a bit at the end on the plane just
uh as a grown man should but um yeah
that is um
yeah yeah I like you know sometimes it's
like um even your own tricks can work
through through a therapist you know I
remember when I was very young
um there was that you I remember being
this you know Wise little [__] that I
knew exactly what to say I knew the
therapists counselor I knew that
relationship so I knew exactly what to
say like I would basically it was like
one therapy session and at the end
they're like oh this kid's fine he's
he's good like he's because I knew
exactly what to say but inside I knew
that I was like lying so I can not have
to deal with this therapy thing you know
and we will trick ourselves into doing
that just like will does in the movie
you know this first five four therapist
or whatever that he goes through he like
pretends to be playing the game and then
he's just actually like being a smart
ass and he's just you know but really
there's something deep down inside that
he that someone who could actually reach
out to him and actually actually talked
to the real him in there could uh you
know have more access to than these
other people would
totally and that's like the not to be
like super cliche with you know the
world we're in and with like hey social
media the more vulnerable you are the
better your audience is like that that
stuff's true like at the end of the day
right and it's like it's it's real it's
almost like you know black magic it's
like use it
willingly like use it and you know for
something decent out there and it's true
right like be the more vulnerable
you are with a therapist your
relationship work anything like
that's where you get to the good stuff
right and I'm not saying to freaking you
know
show up on Monday morning you know with
uh telling your boss everything about
yourself but just trying to kind of
implement that into everything you do I
do with clients all the time right for
work I I show them that I'm not perfect
I uh show them I have two crazy cats
that sometimes need food in the middle
of like an important business call that
that just shows that you're human and
that you're not afraid to show that
you're human right and
um again we don't need to go to the
extreme in that of course the extreme
can happen sometimes and that's where
humility comes in
um
but yeah uh utilizing that so powerful
right it's real like people say social
media you know be vulnerable so your
audience gets it's true it's completely
true right and it's and it's actually
really challenging I think once you
start to do it it works but I do think
it actually is really challenging to do
at the beginning
um but the process in that is
is awesome right just you know yeah yeah
I mean I it's something that I've
learned you know with this podcast I'm
you know I'm pretty close to my 100th
episode here I mean I technically have a
few more recorded that I haven't posted
but
um you know it's it's it's kind of been
this process of trying to make sure I'm
not bullshitting myself you know
sometimes I'll hear myself back I'm
editing on podcasts I'm like I was just
bullshitting like I wouldn't I wasn't
even trying to but you know you notice
it you're like cool God got to stop
doing that whatever it is and it's been
um you know it's been quite a few years
for me but it's always been
something that I try to do you know even
outside of the podcast I've kind of
always been uh I always want to help
people always want to like serve people
and and you know sometimes it could
accidentally come from a place of like
thinking that I'm on a pedestal and like
here's what I know something that's very
true and you need to do what I do you
know and I'm always unwinding that and
I'm always learning that and I'm always
trying to like humility is a great word
for it I'm always like trying to to trip
and fall out loud at the very least you
know and like I'm never trying to if
someone's like well hey you said this
and and then I saw you do this I'm like
yeah she's totally right man yeah I had
to learn that the hard way didn't I you
know and um that's what I'm drawn to
like when I'm listening to like
spiritual lectures or I'm listening to
like these um you know a podcast or
um you know a live conversation that was
filmed or whatever like I don't want to
hear
I'm an expert and I know this it's like
I want to hear their personal experience
and how they discovered it and what
they're learning about themselves
through the process and um that you know
authenticity is such a such a strange
word because you can't like
I'm being authentic you know like
there's not a you know what I mean like
this you gotta really just like let
yourself you know be a fool if you're
being a fool and and stumble through it
and just try to act through honesty
within yourself and that is communicated
that's hard that's that's something that
I'm really drawn to in podcasts is like
someone just really they're not trying
to feed me [__] they're not trying
to sell me something they're not trying
to say like I'm a spiritual leader and
if you want to be happy you got to be
like me and here's the bullet points you
know whatever and uh you know they're
trying to sell you their course or
whatever in in the in the background so
um I think that I think that's I think
we're really really drawn to that and I
think uh I agree our world needs more of
it in a lot of ways
totally and vulnerability I think might
be the first step right just being able
to be like all right I think I know this
and this but let's let's try it and
that's where you learn so much even if
you are let's say you're like a thought
leader you're like a business leader and
it's through the process of what we just
discussed right you've been vulnerable
continuing to go down that path like you
just keep finding more and more and more
truth you know like
um
in in construction we would always say
that the newest person on the crew is
like in many ways the most important
because they often will catch the things
that everyone else won't catch and be
like uh should that thing be open like
that and we're like oh we were too busy
thinking that we you know knew what
we're doing we were being complacent
right so
Yeah by by that's the other part of like
the leadership too that I think is
so Keen not to like
you know say I'm a leader I mean I do
believe I am a leader but like I I
the whole goal I think with leadership
is literally being able to include
everyone at the same time but also being
able to be brutally honest
um and that's one thing that I think
with the leadership today
that's lacking is that
nobody ever wants to tell somebody that
they're not good at something and of
course that's like a horrible way to
like to phrase it right but like it's
always a roundabout but it's like
by showing people and working with them
to explore what their natural strengths
are and to Just Praise them when they
when they you know take risks and to
praise them when they improve on
something there's nothing there's
nothing to a coach boss manager anyone
that's better than seeing somebody who's
not natural skilled to something
eventually break through and be able to
do it that's like the coolest thing and
that's where my take on on God on
religion where I really believe we are
mini creators ourself like I pose this
to my um therapist bow
a year or two ago and I said
are we all supposed to be creators like
are we like
I do I honestly believe in a Creator and
are we supposed to be creative yourself
or are we like made in the image of God
and are we are we also and she's like
yeah you know it's kind of a
philosophical question I don't really
have the answer for it you know like
that's interesting but the more that
life goes on
there's my philosophical thought for the
day is that we are we are all little
mini creators and
um
and it's awesome you know and it's and
yeah so
um
you know if you're if you're gonna yeah
it's it's that plus you know the notion
of like
working with someone and seeing them
persevere it's just it's it's awesome
um kind of see that all play out and
I've I've seen that play out
um many times recently it's and it's
great when it's yourself too right but
you just when you cannot handle
something and
um just go down this tangent a little
bit more it's the biggest thing I see
right now alert course we'll have small
business owners and
many of them are a little bit older
right
um some are young all different ages but
what I think we realize as young people
with technology
it's the same thing as in construction
it's like we don't know everything about
how something works you just kind of
figure it out you just start clicking
buttons you just start asking questions
on this you start calling people you
just kind of figured out and the more
that you step into that
let's say the older person who's doesn't
know how to open up their email box for
example like to us we would laugh at
that right but it's like
you literally just have to turn on the
computer
know what your password is that's a
problem that all of us as human beings
have what is our password for this
there's so many different freaking
passwords it's like so
you know okay we all have that same
problem write down your passwords or put
the same one for everything
and then just start figuring it out
right so
um start clicking around yeah sorry it's
just trying right just
trying
um yeah
yeah I mean yeah it's a it's I feel like
I'm seeing that analogy you know the
typical we've heard it before but you
know instead of looking up the whole
staircase that goes into the clouds and
you're like I know that's where I need
to get to
and you're like it's I can't like I
don't have the even the leg strength to
even climb up there there's no way like
I guess I'll sit here you know no the
answer is take one step what can you do
today don't don't you know you glance up
there remember where you're going I
think but you know what all right right
here I can take one step I don't know
what I don't know my email passwords I I
forgot them I'm stressed out I don't
have anybody I can call well what you
can do is open your laptop okay you got
a home page all right which is maybe I
can just type email and maybe that'll
pop no that didn't work okay maybe I
start clicking on these things you know
you're getting farther take the steps
that you can take you know you can't
just sit down and accept defeat and and
it's when you start doing that and that
that in itself we can have no connection
like in in what we're talking we're
there to like to God to anything else
that could just be faith that things are
going to be okay all right A Little Bit
of Faith that everything's gonna work
out all right that it's all good that
Faith right there
can get you to the top of that staircase
in time when you literally had a minute
left on the clock and the more that we
do that as human beings like oh geez I
have five minutes this meeting I need to
send this off or I need to call my mom
and wish her happy birthday on her
birthday she's about to have hop on a
flight like in in three minutes like
when you start to just try a little bit
you know and and just test it out you
realize
how much the universe and just
everything else helps you and
um you just become empowered to do so
many different things right so it's
great when we start to just you know
spread our wings and just try a little
bit we open up that computer and throw
in
apples one two three and next thing
we're in and I don't use that password
yeah right everybody write that down
that's his password for everything
um yeah I mean it reminds me Lily of
that part you're in a you know uh you
know you're in a situation where a bunch
of people are asking you different
questions and you're overwhelmed but you
kind of give that give yourself that
bird's eye view all right I'm gonna
answer this person right here no you
can't answer everybody all at once cool
accept it give yourself a little bit of
faith that it's still going to be okay
when you just talk to this person and
then cool you answered that question all
right you know Stephanie yeah I agree
blah blah Rodney what did you say again
okay yeah yeah cool now you've just
solved it you didn't have to solve it
all at once you know it's I I like this
saying um and I feel like I say it
probably way too much is uh as you as
you begin to walk the path the path
appears you know it's it's is this brick
this magical brick thing and you can
always see the whole path but you know
you take a step and there's a brick
there's a path and that's like the
inverse of Steve Jobs saying you can
only connect the dots like looking back
backwards right it's like if you're
anyways like he always says that right
like if you if you achieve something
let's say 10 years from now you achieve
what your goal is right now or something
close to it
you can't at the beginning go I'm gonna
get there this way exactly I believe in
Planning by the way plan for sure but
just know that the road is going to
appear in front of you right as you
start to walk it right so it's kind of
the inverse of that one but um that's so
true so true and you and then you start
to like
see the path you start to trust it it's
like oh it's it's lit up I like this
um yeah and then when that's when you
have words like you know faith and um
and and faith and Grace and you know
sometimes I feel Kevin that these words
are
but they're almost locked behind
um what what we think what we think
about religion or what we think about
spirituality what we think about God or
Soul or you know again with any of these
words like um you know if I look at
myself when I was younger I um it's not
that I was like anti-any of these things
but it was just like it just seemed um
you know hopefully it doesn't sound
offensive but it just seemed goofy to me
like whatever that's like I did and so
like even to anytime somebody said the
words Faith around me I thought I knew
what they were talking about they said
God around me I thought I knew what they
were talking about they said Soul or
Spirit or any of these things I thought
I knew what they were talking about in
in these are profound you know their
words but they spark something very very
us very divine within us that yes and
they mean something different to
everyone right so that's why it's like
if your definition of faith is what you
think it is based on like like when you
when you said that there I started to
think what did I use to my definition of
Faith being it's like oh it's you know a
bunch of people in a church and they're
all wearing like you know this type of
clothes that's
you know yeah you're like that's not me
that's what you would think I I know
what it is and I'm not that you know
yeah like that's crazy
exactly and let's try to make let's try
to explore those words
and and this is the thing that I've just
seen so friggin much today
is when I just said ex let's explore
those words somebody go I'm exploring it
and uh I didn't see anything
no let's really try to explore it like
like actually let's open ourselves up
and try to do it
and people always think not everyone but
on the outside oh well I said this and
this so it came off as that we can sense
as human beings if someone's being
genuine we can sense when somebody's
nervous we can sense when somebody's
being a complete a-hole to us and
they're saying it in a really nice way
and when you try really hard at
something you genuinely try to do your
best it shows even if you're crapping it
it shows so
I had somebody the other day they were
completely in the right they had to move
their vehicle I was I was helping this
business and they didn't have no parking
signs but there was one close to it plus
I was really nice to the guy and I just
asked if he could move his car up he's
like hey there's no signs and he was
being a complete a whole like the way he
genuinely was not trying to be nice and
helpful he was like hey man I'm just
trying to help you and it's like
hmm you said those words but uh yeah but
it shows it shows right and that's why
this is one big thing in life and in
business like the positive side of it
that I've taken is like
I used to think if I don't get 100 on
the test you know I'm a bozo or like for
me it was like let's get 80 I just want
to be like middle of the class like you
know in the test but
as time's gone on and you dig into
things
um
I've just began to realize that like our
test now is like how clients are happy
you know the finished product did they
were they approved for the application
were they not it's it's a yes or no it's
one of the other like oks don't really
do anything right so
I approach every project with the same
to do my absolute best and to be honest
and to do maths the best what I've
realized over time is if you try really
hard and I've learned this from our team
too if you
genuinely do your absolute best you
really try and I'm not I don't want to
make it sound like hey you have to stay
up for five days you have to do all this
stuff and walk up this mountain I'm not
saying that I'm just saying if you
actually put your best foot forward and
whatever you do in life have the best
podcast to be the best partner to you
know you know to be honest with your
community you actually try it's crazy
how much that works and how people see
that and how they appreciate that right
it does matter inside how how how are
you trying and like for somebody who's
very results-based and like hey we need
to like disco that
it's an it's incredible how regardless
of an individual's skill set how them
just approaching that every single time
how much it matters I've seen I've seen
people who are the most skilled to 9 or
10 times kill it who eventually just get
you know lose interest or the NH stop
trying how people think oh I did the
same things I've done before what do you
mean it's not it's not it's not good or
it's not there's you can tell when
someone's actually genuinely done their
best and people appreciate that right
like we all we all appreciate that right
like so anyways I'm just I'm just trying
to communicate the inside how we feel in
our approach matters more than anyone
can imagine on the outside it shines
through
so much whether it's Darkness or light
like it just and I don't think that we
and that that's like down that you know
telepathic route of just like hey this
is stuff you can't see prove this that
like it's going down that path but it's
it's so freaking true and uh so
communication is communication is much
deeper than mere words or you know and
of course you know there's body language
and vocal tonality and all these things
that do play into it from a
psychological level but there is
we can send something real I mean it's
it's really just the truth of what we
are we we know what's real and sometimes
we can't put it into words because it's
not really it's a bit beyond words in
some ways we know what's real though
totally and that that like takes me to
like the path of leadership you know and
like and when I say leadership I know we
all think like hey it's uh it's a big
strong leader you know whatever gender
whatever is another one of those words
like God and spirituality we kind of
have a exactly with leadership we think
like hey someone's strong like and maybe
somebody else's Day Clinic could be
completely different right maybe they
had some amazing leaders growing up and
it was different but
regardless the leadership thing it's
like
I watch a lot on like business
um because I think business is so
translatable to everything else in life
um like the challenge is and just
putting yourself out there and finding
your own truth in many different cards
um excuse me um and people a lot of
different people on different podcasts
different
you know
um speeches they talk about how if you
do something and if you start moving
towards it and if you're leading and
you're just you're taking it to where
you need to go people will just
instinctively follow you because they
can tell because first of all that's
actually really rare when somebody's
like anyone can say hey I'm going to
open up this business this and that and
they can start to do different things
it's a whole other thing to say I'm
gonna open this restaurant and it's
going to change the way
that people meet for coffee okay it's
gonna like this is gonna be something
I've I've had this in my dreams I've
spoke to business coaches about this
Consultants I've like I've refined this
this is going to change the way we meet
in person for coffee
totally hypothetical but I'm just giving
you an example right like
if you start to do that and build that
people instinctively that are supposed
to be there will know it's real right
and and follow it and the guy who's
absolute
Looney Tunes like somebody who's like
just making it up
might attract people who want to be
attracted to like that really negative
situation right there might be some
people who either either do actually
have some mental challenges and God
bless them if they were being duped in
by some horrible individual in that
instance but we follow the truth right
it's like the wind we how can I how can
I prove to you the wind is real you know
um
you know now that I'm thinking about it
we can maybe put something up and see
that it not gets knocked over right but
outside of that it's not it's not a
color a lot of the time right but we
know it's real it's the same thing with
um that leadership with god with faith
if sense it be intuitive start to build
it and it's like a muscle right it'll
just start working and you'll just start
to find your own truth and all that and
that's that's really just to kind of
finish things off that's that's my take
on the Jesus thing I know it offends a
lot of people and it's probably the most
persecute religion that there is out
there right now like we talk a lot about
islamophobia which I don't believe you
should be horrible to any religion or to
any group of people as long as they're
you know doing their best to be positive
uh members of you know Humanity but
um you know I I've found my I own truth
in Jesus I Think Jesus was the son of
God it sounds crazy doesn't it like it
sounds so crazy but as you dig into it
and as you feel it
I personally I can feel it like I I and
that's just my own belief right because
when I turn myself over to that I'm LED
it's like the conduit to God into the
holy spirit it's through Jesus and
that's just my own take right like
that's my own but I can literally feel
that and I also see people who reject it
so much and also see people who like how
many times when you see a professional
athlete or anyone you know receive an
award how many times do they stop and
they say
thank you God you know or thank you and
like why is that you know like
who knows that that I I mean I I believe
that um a big part of his faith turning
yourself over to something else that
will help guide you and and that's just
one thing I wish for like the whole
audience and anyone who's watched at
this point and then you know the podcast
is like
start building your own and if you do
have your own keep exploring it right
and like
um you know God is real
and it's and it's not you you know and
it's not to downplay any person I think
that everyone is special that's the
biggest thing in like sports teams and
parents that like that I've always loved
is like the parent who
believes in the kid that's not even
theirs and one thing like when I was I
was 16 I was going to the soccer
tournament I played with this team for
years and I was on this drive and uh
this friend of my dad my friend was
sleeping his dad was driving and he said
you know your mom did a really good job
with you like growing up and just said
like you're you're a great you're a
great kid and this is my last tournament
because I was gonna play rugby after
that
um try to go try to go pro on that and
he really meant it and that like it's
crazy how much that means to certain
people you know and to everyone right to
have somebody who's like you know every
parent wants to probably put their kid
first and like you know it just show
that unconditional love and whatnot for
other things and just that just shows
really what we should be and we're all
interconnected right me doing something
horrible to one person in fact somebody
else and this and that and it's
it's just incredible when uh when people
you know practice that so yeah yeah a
beautiful thing I mean it's pretty
profound that you even have it to this
day you have that memory of this thing
that you know to be important to you of
just him you know maybe he didn't even
think about it profoundly maybe he maybe
he just was communicating from his truth
of like you know what your mom did good
and uh you know you're doing all right
in this sort of thing I feel like I have
my own in my own versions of the same
thing I've um you know in areas where my
parents didn't say certain things I can
definitely pinpoint you know three grown
men older adults in my life that would
tell me things that like would snap me
out of my you know being being a little
[__] you know and I would and I'm like
oh okay all right I'm gonna believe that
and I I remember those to this day and
it's it's a beautiful thing so even
today even today tomorrow like we can
still say those things and we shouldn't
go around making stuff up and doing this
and that but if we can honestly
talk to people and try to inspire them
through just being yourselves and like
pointing out like hey that was
incredible like that was whatever you
did right there that was incredible what
was that and you know or
being honest with Bill hey that could
have been better you know just trying to
be genuine and honest with people it's
incredible how much a that comes back to
you and B how that can help people in
today right like look at what you just
said some grown men even the last few
years you know maybe validated things
that you need to validated when you're
younger and that's it's nothing against
your family something is my family
that's one of the biggest things when I
was going through therapy I was like
this is nothing it's my family I love
and they're like no we get that we get
that
so my mom beat me when I was uh four
right no just kidding yeah yeah yeah I
mean our parents are just on their own
path as well you know we're all just
we're all just together on this journey
we're all just you know again ramdas
like I've mentioned he says we're all
just walking each other home and it
really is that you know there's there's
this current that's going through and
we're all maybe not aware how our
interactions are affecting each other
and like very deeply profound ways but
when we're acting from truth I think
that we're all falling back into that
current you know we're not trying to go
against the river and go against the
current that's forcing against us it's
lifting your legs up and just I'm going
to say that you know I'm you know what
you did good job kid you know or you
know what I I see better than you and
and uh you know I had teachers I had a
principal who pulled me to the side
um after I like had just I just I
basically smoked a bunch of weed and
then I went to the school dance and he
didn't get me in trouble but he pulled
me to the side and basically told me
like hey I don't know if you notice or
not but uh people listen to you you're a
leader and now like you know at the time
I'm like okay bro like you know cool and
to this day to this day I notice when
I'm rambling on people are listening to
me and so I should take responsibility
and that's you know I think that's what
a leader should do
um Kevin we are getting up here right in
time I would I would love to um just
just very quickly can you tell people
where to find your business where to
find your website where to find more on
you all of this for sure our website is
bsbcon.com that stands for Black Sheep
business Consulting
um I I love chatting with people I love
you know just general discussion so I'm
really accessible I always try to be I
always tell people if you want to get a
hold of me call me because I was
answering my phone or I was calling
people back emails I can let those get
push down uh you know uh but you can
contact me by email too but yeah
um you know we write business plans I in
the next minute or two I'm gonna go into
this other call with this very nice
gentleman uh looking for a business plan
and
yeah I'm just uh I wanna I Wanna Be You
know the
there's a guy from The Matrix
I want to be Morpheus no uh I forget his
name he's a Canadian actor but he's just
a real like down to earth
um individual right and like that's I
want to be in a point where I can make
change where I can be successful at the
same time
um
I want to be somebody who's just as
normal as you could be because that's
how I feel like
you know what what I meant to do and to
just do my best and make mistakes on the
public stage you know like that's that's
where I really want to go and anything I
can do to help other people I I want to
try to try to do
um so yeah thanks so much for for your
time today it was a great great time
being on the show and um you're doing a
great thing awesome yeah thank you
brother I appreciate you saying it um
yeah yeah we'll be in touch I would love
to pick your pick your brain about um
you know my own business and my own my
own kind of plans here so um yeah I
would love to set that up and uh maybe
we should hop on a phone call so I don't
uh text or email you but yeah if you
have time the next few days
um you know I I would love to uh I would
love to coordinate that man I'd love to
chat with you about that sweet dude
let's do it for sure thank you so much
man it was great talking to you dude I'm
excited to see it I know it might take
weeks or months so you actually post it
but that'd be cool awesome yeah we'll
see I think I'm gonna post this one a
bit sooner all right cool all right
thanks so much man have a good day
thanks Jake thank you take care brother
listeners love yourselves peace out
conversation
at what age should we learn to have
better conversations with ourselves
[Music]
knowledge is power
reality is
[Music]